# File Manager

This project is a **File Manager** application developed using Python and Tkinter. It allows users to manage files and folders with a graphical user interface (GUI), including functions like file creation, deletion, searching, and navigating directories.

## Features

- **File and Folder Listing**: View files and directories in a specified path.
- **Create Folders**: Easily create new folders through the interface.
- **Delete Files/Folders**: Select files or folders to delete.
- **Search Functionality**: Search for files within a directory by name.
- **Drag-and-Drop Window**: Move the application window around by dragging.
- **Fullscreen Toggle**: Switch between normal and fullscreen view.
- **Minimize Option**: Minimize the window to the taskbar.
- **Double Click to Open Files/Folders**: Open files or navigate into folders by double-clicking them.
- **Toolbar Controls**: Includes buttons for creating folders, deleting files, and toggling fullscreen.

## Requirements

- **Python 3.x**
- **Tkinter** (Usually included with Python by default)
- **shutil** and **os** (Standard Python libraries for file handling)

## Installation

To run the File Manager, follow these steps:

1. Clone the repository or download the project files.

   ```bash
   git clone <repository-url>



---

This `README.md` provides a comprehensive overview of your project, including installation instructions, usage, and the files that make up the project. You can include this in your project to help others understand how to set it up and use it effectively.
